A Finding Aid to the Francis Patrick Garvan Papers, 1867, 1912-1953, in the Archives of American Art AAA.garvfran
Archives of American Art
- Inventory, 1928-circa 1940s; Series 5; 26 Linear feet Boxes 17-43
  - Inventory Cards, 1201-1220 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Inventory Cards, 1221-1240 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Inventory Cards, 1241-1260 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Inventory Cards, 1261-1280 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Inventory Cards, 1281-1300 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Inventory Cards, 1301-1320 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Inventory Cards, 1321-1340 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Inventory Cards, 1341-1360 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Inventory Cards, 1361-1380 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Inventory Cards, 1381-1400 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Inventory Cards, 1401-1600 Mixed Items, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Inventory Cards, American Pottery, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 23-26)
  - Inventory Cards, American Pottery 01-50, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Inventory Cards, American Pottery 51-100, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Inventory Cards, American Pottery 101-150, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Inventory Cards, American Pottery 151-200, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Inventory Cards, American Pottery 201-250, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Inventory Cards, Beds, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Inventory Cards, Benches and Stools, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Inventory Cards, Bennington Pottery, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 8-10)
  - Inventory Cards, Bookcases, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Inventory Cards, Boxes, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Inventory Cards, Brass, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Inventory Cards, Candlesticks, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Inventory Cards, Chairs, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Inventory Cards, Chests, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Inventory Cards, China, 1930s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 17-24)
  - Inventory Cards, China, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 1-6)
  - Inventory Cards, Chinese Porcelain, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 7-8)
  - Inventory Cards, Clocks, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Inventory Cards, Coins and Medals, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 10-12)
  - Inventory Cards, Copper, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 13-14)
  - Inventory Cards, Cabinets and Cupboards, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 15-16)
  - Inventory Cards, Desks, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Inventory Cards, Duplicate Cards, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Inventory Cards, Early American Brass, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 19-21)
  - Inventory Cards, Early American Brass, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Inventory Cards, English 01-20, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Inventory Cards, English 21-40, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Inventory Cards, English 41-60, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Inventory Cards, English 61-80, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Inventory Cards, English 81-100, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Inventory Cards, English 101-120, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Inventory Cards, English 121-140, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Inventory Cards, English 141-160, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Inventory Cards, English 161-180, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Inventory Cards, English 181-200, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Inventory Cards, English 201-300, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 01-50, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 51-100, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 101-150, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 151-200, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 201-250, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 251-300, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 301-350, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 351-400, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 401-425, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 426-450, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 451-500, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 501-550, 1930s-1940s (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 551-600, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 601-650, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 651-700, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 701-750, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 751-800, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 801-850, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 851-900, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 901-950, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 951-1000, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 1001-1050, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery 1051-1115, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Inventory Cards, English Pottery, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 12-13)
  - Inventory Cards, Fabrics and Rugs, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Inventory Cards, Foreign Furniture, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Inventory Cards, Foreign Pottery, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Inventory Cards, Glass, 1930s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 18-23)
  - Inventory Cards, Glass, 1930s-1940s (Box 33, Folder 1-19)
  - Inventory Cards, HIghboys and Lowboys, 1930s-1940s (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Inventory Cards, Irish Pottery, 1930s-1940s (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Inventory Cards, Lamps, 1930s-1940s (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Inventory Cards, Lamps and Lanterns, 1930s-1940s (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Inventory Cards, Lowestoff, 1930s-1940s (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
  - Inventory Cards, Lustre, 1930s-1940s (Box 34, Folder 5-8)
  - Inventory Cards, Miscellaneous, 1930s-1940s (Box 34, Folder 9-17)
  - Inventory Cards, Miscellaneous, 1930s-1940s (Box 35, Folder 1-5)
  - Inventory Cards, Mirror, 1930s-1940s (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
  - Inventory Cards, Modern Furniture, 1930s-1940s (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Inventory Cards, Needlework, 1930s-1940s (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Inventory Cards, O'Reilly Warehouse, 1930s-1940s (Box 35, Folder 10-18)
  - Inventory Cards, O'Reilly Warehouse, 1930s-1940s (Box 36, Folder 1-14)
  - Inventory Cards, Paintings, 1930s-1940s (Box 36, Folder 15-18)
  - Inventory Cards, Paintings, 1930s-1940s (Box 37, Folder 1-15)
  - Inventory Cards, Pewter, 1930s-1940s (Box 37, Folder 16-19)
  - Inventory Cards, Pewter, 1930s-1940s (Box 38, Folder 1-12)
  - Inventory Cards, Picture Frames, 1930s-1940s (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Inventory Cards, Pottery, 1930s-1940s (Box 38, Folder 14-15)
  - Inventory Cards, Prints, 1930s-1940s (Box 38, Folder 16-17)
  - Inventory Cards, Settees and Couches, 1930s-1940s (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Inventory Cards, Sheffield Pottery, 1930s-1940s (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Inventory Cards, Sideboards, 1930s-1940s (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Inventory Cards, Silver, 1930s-1940s (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
  - Inventory Cards, Silver and Pewter, 1930s-1940s (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Inventory Cards, Staffordshire, 1930s-1940s (Box 39, Folder 4-17)
  - Inventory Cards, Steigle Glass, 1930s-1940s (Box 39, Folder 18-19)
  - Inventory Cards, Tables, 1930s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 1-9)
  - Inventory Cards, Textiles, 1930s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Inventory Cards, Tiles, 1930s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Inventory Cards, Tin, 1930s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Inventory Cards, Wood Carvings, 1930s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Inventory Cards, Washstands, 1930s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Inventory Cards, Wrought Iron, 1930s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 15-18)
  - Inventory Cards, Old Catalog Cards, 1930s-1940s (Box 41, Folder 1-4)
  - Inventory Cards, Old Catalog Cards, 1930s-1940s (Box 42, Folder 1-4)
  - Inventory Cards, Old Catalog Cards, 1930s-1940s (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Printed Material, 1867; 1926-1949; Series 6; 1 Linear feet Box 43-44, 46
  Printed material includes art catalogues which range from small personal collections to those of considerable size and extent. Also found are art magazines and bulletins from various art or historical organizations. One item of note is an unbound copy of The Address of the City of New York to George Washington, and his replies, New York 1867. This is one of only 75 printed copies of this publication and includes a reproduction of the handwritten letter as well as a portrait print of George Washington.
  - Apollo Journal, 1933 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Association of Fine Arts at Yale University, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Boulton & Paul Ltd., 1929 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Bulletin of Ft. Ticonderoga Museum, 1948-1949 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Catalogues, Anderson Galleries, 1940s (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Catalogues, Books, Manuscripts, Engravings, and Autographed Letters, 1928 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Catalogues, Books on Ireland, 1928 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Catalogues, Crossroads of Sport, 1948-1949 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Catalogues, Currier & Ives, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Catalogues, Cyril Andrade Collection, 1922 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Catalogues, Early American Silver, Pewter, Glass, and China, 1940s (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Catalogues, Fine Old English Silver, 1931 (Box 43, Folder 13-15)
  - Catalogues, Fine Old English Silver, 1931 (Box 44, Folder 1-4)
  - Catalogues, J. Horrace Harding, 1937 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Catalogues, James A. Stillman, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Catalogues, John Quidor, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Catalogues, Sportsman's Miscellany, 1948-1949 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Catalogues, Thomas Eakins, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Catalogues, Victoria and Albert Museum, 1931 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Chemical Foundation, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Connoisseur Magazine, 1937 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - George Washington, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    Oversized materials housed in box 46.
  - Holme Lacy Herefordshire, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Homewood House, 1932 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Knoedler Art Galleries, 1948 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Magazines, 1948; 1947 (Box 44, Folder 17-18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1940s (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Mount Vernon Ladies Association of the Union, 1948 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - New York Historical Society Quarterly, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - News Clippings, 1930s (Box 44, Folder 22-23)
  - Wightman Memorial Art Gallery, 1934 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Yale, 1930-1935 (Box 44, Folder 25-31)
  - Oversized Address of the City of New York to George Washington, and his replies, from Box 44, Folder 13, 1867 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Yale, from Box 44, Folder 25-31, 1932-1935 (Box 46, Folder 8)
- Writings, 1930s; Series 7; 3 Folders Box 44
  This series includes a few excerpts of Garvan's writings on decorative arts.
  - Essay, "Pottery and Porcelain", 1930s (Box 44, Folder 32)
  - Manuscript, "The Present State of Old English Furniture", 1930s (Box 44, Folder 33)
  - Manuscript, Untitled, 1930s (Box 44, Folder 34)
- Photographic Materials, 1930s-1940s; Series 8; 1 Linear feet Boxes 45-45, BV 47
  The photographic materials includes contains photographs, negatives, and photograph albums of Garvan's collection. Not all negatives have existing prints. The series also includes a few family portraits of distant relatives to the Garvan Family.
  - American Art Association, 1931 (Box 44, Folder 35-36)
  - Garvan Family Portraits, 1946-1949 (Box 44, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Decorative Arts, 1930s-1940s (Box 44, Folder 38-40)
  - Photographs of Paintings, 1930s-1940s (Box 44, Folder 41-43)
  - Photo Negatives, undated (Box 45, Folder 1-9)
  - Photo Album of St. John's College, circa 1930s (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Photograph Album, Wightman Memorial Art Gallery, circa 1930s (Box BV 47)